Well, it’s finally happened.
ついに あなたの夢見ていた理想の人が
現われました
You think you’ve found the person
of your dreams, and now . . .
そして—
You’re hopelessly in love!
Or are you?
でも 本当に？
How can you tell if it’s really love?
本当の愛かどうか
どうすれば分かるでしょうか？
The key is:
そのかぎは 違いを知ることです
You’ve got to learn
the differences between attraction,
つまり 一目ぼれと……恋と……
本物の愛の違いです
infatuation,
and actual love.
一目ぼれには
見ることが関係しています
Attraction is based on what you see.
You know, how a person looks and acts.
相手の外見やしぐさに惹かれるのです
The problem is, what you see
でも 見た目と中身は必ずしも
同じではありません
isn’t always what you get.
So then,
では 恋とは何ですか？
what is infatuation?
Infatuation is not only about what you see;
恋には 見ることに加えて
感じることが関係します
it’s about how you feel.
夢見心地になるかもしれません
You may have romantic feelings.
でも そういう気持ちは
変わることがあります
But those feelings can change . . .
and fast!
しかもすぐに！
Infatuation may seem like love.
恋が愛のように思えることがあります
But because it’s based only
でも それは一時の感情に過ぎないので—
on how you feel at the moment, . . .
簡単に壊れてしまいます
it can just fall apart.
では ずっと続く本当の愛かどうか
どうすれば分かるでしょうか？
So how do you know if it’s really love?
One that will last?
本当の愛は2人が親切を示し合い よく働き—
Real love grows
when two people are kind,
hard-working,
霊的な価値観を共有するときに
育まれます
and share the same spiritual outlook.
At 1 Corinthians 13:5,
聖書のコリント第一 13章5節によると
本当の愛は“自分の利を求め”ません
the Bible says that real love
‘doesn’t look for its own interests.’
For example,
that guy you like so much,
例えば あなたの大好きな男の子は—
どんなお金の使い方をしますか？
how does he handle money?
Does he have to drink alcohol
お酒がないと楽しめない人ですか？
to have a good time?
What are his goals?
彼の目標は何ですか？
Is he really working toward them?
その目標に向かって努力していますか？
Or is he all talk and no action?
それとも 口先だけでしょうか？
And what about that girl
you just can’t stop thinking about?
あなたの頭から離れない女の子は
どうですか？
Who are her friends?
どんな人を友達にしていますか？
And how does she treat them?
友達にどう接していますか？
How does she treat her family?
家族にどう接していますか？
There’s a lot to learn about another person.
だれかを本当に知るには
時間がかかります！
It takes time!
So before you get swept off your feet,
ですから 好きになる前に
思い出しましょう
remember:
Attraction is based on what you see.
一目ぼれは見ること—
Infatuation is based on what you feel.
恋は感じることに左右されます
But real love . . .
でも本当の愛は—
is based on what you know.
知ることが基盤になるのです